# Mariia Danilova

# QA Engineer (manual) remotely

#### CONTACTS



+34615666088



https://www.linkedin.com/in/danilovamariak/



danilova.maria.k@gmail.com

Barcelona, Spain

Two years ago I decided to switch my profile from market researcher to get into software testing.

Now I'm working as a crowdtester and I'm looking for a remote project where I can implement and extend my skills, experience and professional growth in QA. It's always interesting to investigate something.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE IN SOFTWARE TESTING

Testbirds testbirds.com - Crowdtester

January, 2021 - present

Web and mobile testing

#### Tasks:

- UI, UX testing
- Functional testing
- · Use cases testing
- · Cross browser testing
- · Bug reports

## **Yandex Practicum - QA Engineer (student)**

May 2022 - September 2022

fulfilled four training projects (web/mobile testing, frontend/backend testing)

#### Tasks:

- · used EP, BVA, PW, S&T techniques
- created check-lists, test-cases, bug reports
- used Charles и Chrome DevTools (JS errors, checking if a page is implemented by design, errors localization, XSS checking, throttling, overrides etc)
- · fulfilled mobile testing with Android Studio
- performed API testing with Postman (CRUD requests, collections running, setting variables dynamically like for query parameters, headers, and body; writing Postman tests using Chai.js BDD assertions, Newman test run)
- used Terminal to connect to remote server via SSH
- · connected to database and used PostgreSQL for testing

### OTHER EXPERIENCE

• GfK-Russia, GfK.com (international market research company) Senior Researcher/Research Project Manager (Healthcare market research)

- October 2007 - February 2013

Tasks:

- Research design, timing, cost calculation
- Designing research instruments (sample, questionnaire, specifications for the field department, encoding department, data processing department)
- Project management
- Analysis reports and presentations to the clients Carried out different full-cycle market researches for Novartis, GSK, Shering Plau, NicoMED, Elly Lilly, Pfizer



#### **SKILLS**

Postman

DevTools Charles

Android Studio **GIT** 

Jira **TestRail** 

Test documentation

Test design techniques

Knowledge of client-server architecture

Basic SQL knowledge (CRUD, DDL, DML)

Knowledge of Agile methodologies

Basics of Python

CSS, HTML basics

#### **EDUCATION**

Master's Degree in Sociology Saint Petersburg State University 2003

#### **COURSES**

 Yandex Practicum QA Engineer, 2022 r

Udemy

Python 3 Postman Git

· Stepik.org Python

#### **LANGUAGES**

- English (upper intermediate)
- · Spanish (DELE A2, everyday using)
- Catala (A2 certificate)
- Lithuanian (A2 certificate)
- Russian (native)

https://github.com/catsagainst/QA\_portfolio